If you have also got your insurance done from these six insurance companies,
then
definitely watch this video till the end. You will see that
many big insurance companies of India are under
investigation for tax evasion
and the matter is being investigated by the
Director General of GST Validation, the GI.
In the ongoing investigation regarding tax evasion, six insurance companies have been
sent notices of a huge amount of about 3000 crores. Let us
tell you that the
name of ICC Lombard is also included in this list. Let us tell you
that the reason for the notice of crores sent to these insurance companies is
that
they
collected commission from the insurance company on the insurance premium but did
not pay GST. Although the
GST officer has not mentioned the name of any company,
but he definitely
told that the notices sent were of about 3000 crores.
After adding interest and penalty, the
amount of the notice would be 500 crores. But one of these six major
insurance companies, ICC
Lombard,
itself informed Sher Bajwa about the notice received for GST evasion
and told that it has received a
tax notice of around 1729 crores. The
company also told that this notice was issued in
July.  The
company is also preparing to respond to the notice received from GST regarding the rain insurance premium received between 2017 and March 2022.
See, before this, the
government insurance company, Lik, also
came under the scanner of GST investigation and along with Lik, many
insurance companies are already
facing investigation regarding input tax credit.
Regarding this, Lik was
sent a notice of around 2090 crores a few days ago,
which included interest and penalty. Lik is accused of
not reversing the input tax credit on the premium received. Due to
not reversing the ITC on the same premium,
many insurance companies are under the target of tax officials.
Tax insurance companies
also say that many companies have
claimed input tax credit on the basis of fake bills received from intermediaries and agents, the
investigation of which is
going on in the Mumbai, Ghaziabad, Bengaluru offices of DG.
What do you have to say on this,
please write in the comment section. If you
liked my video, then do not forget to like and share.
[Music]
[Praise]